Finding aid for the Smith College Club of South Shore, MA records CA.MS.00331
Smith College Archives
Smith College Club of South Shore, MA records
1937-1992
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of South Shore, MA
CA.MS.00331
1.667 linear feet (4 containers)
The Smith College Club of South Shore, MA has been an active club since the late 1930s. Its records contain minutes, secretary reports, newsletters, and events materials.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College Club of South Shore, MA has been an active club since the late 1930s, hosting social events for Smith College alumnae, raising money for the scholarship fund, mainly through pecan sales, and recruiting students to Smith through social events and book awards. The club's social events range from Smith faculty lectures to luncheons and the annual meeting, as well as events with other local Smith Clubs and clubs of other colleges.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains board files, membership lists and updates, alumnae association papers, and recruiting materials. The papers span from 1937 until 1987, and concentrate mainly on the Club's activities and records from the 1960s and 1980s.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series:
Series I: Board Files
Series II: Membership
Series III: Alumnae Association
Series IV: Recruiting
Series V: General Files
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith College Club of South Shore, MA records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- Series I: Board Files
  - Board Meetings, 1937-54 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1988-91 (Box 1)
  - Club Notebook (14 Folders), 1985-87 (Box 1)
  - Club President's Handbook, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Secretary's Reports (2 Folders), 1937-55 (Box 1)
  - Secretary's Reports (5 folders), 1959-68 (Box 2)
  - Secretary's Minutes, 1954-59 (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1985; 1989 (Box 2)
  - Press Releases (2 Folders), 1964-89; undated (Box 2)
- Series II: Membership
  - Club Alumnae Lists, 1938-39; 1984-86 (Box 3)
  - Club Alumnae List Updates, 1985-91 (Box 3)
  - Club Alumnae List, undated (Box 3)
- Series III: Alumnae Association
  - Alumnae Council, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Bed and Breakfast Program, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Clubs Committee Rotating Advisory Group Meeting, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Speakers Program, 1990-91 (Box 3)
  - Fundraising, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Career Development Handbook, 1978; undated (Box 3)
- Series IV: Recruiting
  - Book Award Materials, 1986; undated (Box 3)
  - Candidates Committee Information, 1979-1985; undated (Box 3)
  - Visiting Year Materials, 1985; undated (Box 3)
  - Recruiting Handbooks, undated (Box 3)
  - Interviewing for Smith, undated (Box 3)
  - Admissions Brochures, 1983-1987 (Box 3)
  - Smith College Publications, 1980; 1984 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3)
- Series V: General Files
  - Newsletters, 1939-45; 1985-90 (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 4)
  - Fundraising: Annual Pecan Report, 1989-90 (Box 4)
  - Fundraising: Holiday Treats, 1987; 1991-92 (Box 4)
  - Jill Ker Conway Visit, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Donald Robinson Lecture, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Economic Planning Group, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Critic's Choice Club Information, 1991; undated (Box 4)
  - Boston League of Smith College Clubs, 1984-85 (Box 4)
  - Other Clubs Information, 1989; undated (Box 4)
  - Smith-Mt. Holyoke Meeting, 1984 (Box 4)
  - SEA Education Association, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Questionnaire Results, undated (Box 4)
  - Noteables a cappella, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
  - CDO Information, undated (Box 4)
  - Sophia Smith College Catalogue and Correspondence with Mary-Elizabeth Murdock, 1984 (Box 4)